Connecticut Soldiers Collection
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Connecticut Soldiers Collection, Peter Lukoff Papers.
undated, 1944-1945.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Lukoff, Peter.
1 linear foot.
Peter Lukoff, Company C, 48th Armor Infantry Battalion, lived in Norwich, Connecticut. The bulk of the collection documents Lukoff's experiences from training in the United States (South Carolina) and his activities in France, Belgium, Germany and England from 1944-1945.
MSS20050143
Biography
Peter Lukoff, of Norwich, Connecticut, served in Company C, 48th Armor Infantry Battalion date from April 1944 through June 1945. Prior to his war service he was employed by the Hartford-Connecticut Trust Company, Thames Branch.
Scope and Content
The bulk of the collection documents Lukoff's experiences from training in the United States (South Carolina) and his activities in France, Belgium, Germany and England. Also included are letters and cards from his wife, Alma, and two children, Philip and Barbara. Lukoff was wounded in action at the Battle of the Bulge and separated from his unit for a short period of time.
Arrangement
Series I: Correspondence ( undated, 1944-1945 )
Series II: Other papers ( undated, 1944-1945 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut history. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Lukoff, Peter.
Subjects:
Soldiers--Connecticut--Correspondence.; World War, 1938-1945--Personal narratives--Connecticut.; Norwich (Conn.)--Family and personal papers.; Connecticut--Family and personal papers.; Norwich (Conn.)
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Financial Records.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was purchased in 2001.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Correspondence, undated, 1944-1945
  - undated (Box 2:, Folder 25)
  - 1944 April (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - 1944 May (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - 1944 June (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - 1944 July (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - 1944 September (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - 1944 October (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - 1944 November (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - 1944 December (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - 1945 January (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - 1945 February (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - 1945 March (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - 1945 April (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - 1945 May (Box 2:, Folder 13)
  - 1945 June (Box 2:, Folder 14)
  - To Peter from Alma, undated (Box 2:, Folder 15)
  - To Peter from Alma, 194 (Box 2:, Folder 16)
  - To Peter from Alma, 1944 March (Box 2:, Folder 17)
  - To Peter from Alma, 1944 May (Box 2:, Folder 18)
  - To Peter from Alma, 1944 June (Box 2:, Folder 19)
  - Friends and Family, undated (Box 2:, Folder 20)
  - Friends and Family, 1944-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 21)
- Series II: Other papers, undated, 1944-1945
  - Ephemera, undated (Box OS, 2:, Folder 22)
  - Financial records, 1944-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 23)
  - Military publications, 1944 (Box 2:, Folder 24)